NAYAN KUMAR

OBJECTIVE

Experienced DevOps Engineer with 4-5 years of specialized expertise in CI/CD pipelines, infrastructure automation, and cloud services, complemented by 12 years of comprehensive infrastructure engineering experience. Seeking a challenging role to utilize my skills and contribute to the success and growth of a forward-thinking organization.

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

- Hiker
- Gardening & Landscaping
- Technology Enthusiast

KEY SKILLS

- Automation & Configuration Management: Ansible, Puppet, Chef, SALTSTACK
- CI/CD: Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD, CircleCI, Travis CI
- Cloud Services: AWS, Azure & Google Cloud Platform
- Scripting & Programming: Bash, Python, PowerShell, Ruby
- Infrastructure as Code (IaC): Terraform, CloudFormation
- Containerization & Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift
- Monitoring & Logging: Prometheus, Grafana.
- Version Control: Git, SVN
- Networking & Security: TCP/IP, DNS, firewalls, VPNs.
- Collaboration & Communication: Jira, Confluence, Slack.
- Operating Systems: Linux (CentOS, Ubuntu), Windows Server
- Database Management: MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB
- Virtualization: VMWare, VirtualBox, Hyper-V, KVM

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior System Administrator Megamax Services Pvt Ltd | Dec 2021 - Present

Client: Cargowise

CargoWise is a powerful, deeply integrated global logistics execution platform that makes trade easy.

- Troubleshooting application error/warning logs and apply proper remediation.
- Build & Manage Grafana dashboard to monitor server performance/metrics.
- Run SQL Queries to track stuck messaging queue.
- Quarterly Application version upgrade
- DB Backup & Restore.
- Create powershell scripts to automate reports.

Senior System Administrator Catchpoint Systems Pvt Ltd | Jul 2019 - Oct 2021

Description: Catchpoint Systems has a proprietary site performance monitoring tool.

- Commissioning Windows & Linux servers of on premise & hosted.
- Troubleshooting server issues by referring event viewer logs.
- Handling technical escalations.
- Software deployment.
- Capturing and analyzing Wireshark packets to identify network issues.
- Usage terraform perform server builds according to standard configurations.
- Using packer tool to create server images periodically.
- Using SALT master tool for remote execution commands to minions.

EDUCATION

- SSLC
 - May 2005 | Poorna Prajna High School
- Pre-University
 May 2007 | Sheshadripuram PU College
- Diploma in E&C
 May 2012 | Acharya Institute of technology

VOLUNTEER & RECOGNITIONS

- Actively engaged in the employee engagement group, organizing monthly events that foster team building and collaboration among employees from various departments.
- Received consistent recognition and appreciation throughout my career for demonstrating dedication, excellence, and commitment to my work.

CONTACT



nayankumar.me



nayan.kumar.ys@outlook.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/nayanlinkdn/



https://github.com/nayan-kumar-ghub



Senior Customer Care Engineer Aspect Software | Aug 2018 - Jul 2019

Description: Aspect software develops and manages web/cloud-based call center solutions.

- Handling server environments of on premise and hosted.
- Troubleshooting product issues by referring event viewer logs.
- Executing SQL queries for resolving application issues.
- Product implementation & server configurations to clients.

Senior Engineer Mindtree Ltd | Sep 2014 - Aug 2018

Clients: Volvo IT India, Kellogg's IT

Description: Faros is an intranet application for Volvo Group.

- Handling production and local server environments.
- Scheduling backups and Using TSM.
- Troubleshooting Windows MQ and IBM web sphere MQ.
- Necessary scripting for backups and MQ thresholds.
- Building & configuring local servers according to requirement from team.
- Production Deployment.
- Security and critical patching.
- AWS EC2, Cloud Watch, Amazon S3, Identity & Access Management.

System Administrator dWise Solutions Pvt Ltd | Jun 2012 - Aug 2014

Client: OneEHR & Healthi9.

Description: OneEHR and Healthi9 are cloud-based applications.

- Desktop support engineer to setup applications across hospitals in India.
- Configuring windows webservers and database servers.
- Server/Network troubleshooting.
- Installation of various tools like MYSQL, MSSQL, Apache tomcat, Adobe Flex, PHP.
- Configuring in house datacenter using VMware EXSi.
- Configuring and managing Switches & routers.
- Structured networking planning.